In the race to document the species on Earth before they go extinct, researchers and citizen scientists have collected billions of records.
为了赶在地球上的物种灭绝之前将它们记录下来，研究人员和公民科学家争分夺秒，已经收集了数十亿条记录。
Today, most records of biodiversity are in the form of photos, videos, and other digital records.
如今，大多数生物多样性记录都以照片、视频和其他数字记录的形式存在。
Though they are useful for detecting shifts in the number and variety of species in an area, a new Stanford study has found that this type of record is not perfect.
尽管这些记录有助于发现一个地区内物种数量和种类的变化，但斯坦福大学的一项新研究发现，这类记录并不完美。
“With the rise of technology it is easy for people to make observations of different species with the aid of a mobile application,” said Barnabas Daru, who is lead author of the study and assistant professor of biology in the Stanford School of Humanities and Sciences.
“随着技术的兴起，人们借助手机应用程序就能轻松地观察不同的物种，”该研究的第一作者、斯坦福大学人文与科学学院生物学助理教授巴纳巴斯·达鲁说。
“These observations now outnumber the primary data that come from physical specimens, and since we are increasingly using observational data to investigate how species are responding to global change, I wanted to know: Are they usable?”
“这些观察记录如今在数量上已超过来自实物标本的原始数据，而且由于我们越来越多地利用观察数据来研究物种如何应对全球变化，我想知道：这些数据能用吗？”
Using a global dataset of 1.9 billion records of plants, insects, birds, and other animals, Daru and his team tested how well these data represent actual global biodiversity patterns.
达鲁和他的团队利用一个包含19亿条植物、昆虫、鸟类和其他动物记录的全球数据集，检验了这些数据能在多大程度上反映真实的全球生物多样性格局。
“We were particularly interested in exploring the aspects of sampling that tend to bias data, like the greater likelihood of a citizen scientist taking a picture of a flowering plant instead of the grass right next to it,” said Daru.
“我们特别感兴趣的是探究采样中容易使数据产生偏差的那些方面，比如公民科学家更有可能拍下一株开花的植物，而不是紧挨着它的草，”达鲁说。
Their study revealed that the large number of observation-only records did not lead to better global coverage.
他们的研究揭示，大量仅基于观察的记录并没有带来更好的全球覆盖。
Moreover, these data are biased and favor certain regions, time periods, and species.
此外，这些数据存在偏差，偏向某些地区、时间段和物种。
This makes sense because the people who get observational biodiversity data on mobile devices are often citizen scientists recording their encounters with species in areas nearby.
这不难理解，因为用移动设备获取生物多样性观察数据的人往往是公民科学家，他们记录的是自己在附近地区遇见的物种。
These data are also biased toward certain species with attractive or eye-catching features.
这些数据还偏向于某些特征吸引人或引人注目的物种。
What can we do with the imperfect datasets of biodiversity?
我们能用这些不完美的生物多样性数据集做些什么呢？
“Quite a lot,” Daru explained.
“能做的有很多，”达鲁解释说。
“Biodiversity apps can use our study results to inform users of oversampled areas and lead them to places — and even species — that are not well-sampled.
“生物多样性应用程序可以利用我们的研究结果，告诉用户哪些区域采样过度，并把他们引向采样不足的地方——甚至是采样不足的物种。
To improve the quality of observational data, biodiversity apps can also encourage users to have an expert confirm the identification of their uploaded image.”
为了提高观察数据的质量，生物多样性应用程序还可以鼓励用户请专家确认他们所上传图片的识别结果。”